Finding Aid for the Ferdinand Canning Scott Schiller Papers, ca. 1870-1940
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
- Articles, Pamphlets, Lectures, and Symposia
  - Meeting of the Aristotelian Society. April 8, 1918., 3 copies. Two of which have holograph corrections. (Box 13)
  - On arguing in a circle. Meeting of the Aristotelian Society. July 4, 1921., 1 copy with holograph corrections. (Box 13)
  - On preserving appearances. Mind, vol.12, N.S., no.47., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - On some philosophic assumptions in the investigation of the problem of a future life. Proceedings of the Society for Psychical Research, Part 36. February 1900., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - On the conception of 'ENE'PTEIA 'AKINHEI'AE Mind, vol.9, N.S., no.36., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Our critic criticized. Written with Major Leonard Darwin and C.J. Bond. Eugenics Review. January 1914., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Plato or Protagoras? [pamphlet]. Oxford, Blackwell. 1908., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Plato or Protagoras? [reply to review by Professor Burnet]. Mind, vol.17, N.S., no.68., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Pragmatism and pseudo-pragmatism. Mind, vol.15, N.S., no.59., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - The present phase of 'idealist' philosophy. Mind, vol.19, N.S., no.73., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Professor Henry Jones on 'reflective thought and religion'. Hibbert Journal. January 1903., 2 copies. one of which has holograph corrections. (Box 13)
  - Professor Ross on Aristotle's self-refutation. Mind, vol.23, N.S., no.92., 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - Psychology and knowledge. Mind, vol.16, N.S., no.62., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Psychology and logic. Psychology and the Sciences. n.d., 1 copy with holograph corrections. (Box 13)
  - The rationalistic conception of truth. Proceedings of the Aristotelian Society. 1909., 4 copies. (Box 13)
  - Realism, pragmatism, and William James. Mind, vol.24, N.S., no.96., 2 copies. one of which has holograph corrections. (Box 13)
  - Relevance. Mind, vol.21, N.S., no.82., 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - The ruin of Rome and its lessons for us. Eugenics Review. April, 1925., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Science and life. The Hibbert Journal. n.d., 1 copy. with holograph corrections. (Box 13)
  - Science and religion. Pan-Anglican Papers. 1908., 3 copies. (Box 13)
  - Scientific method in psychical research. The Psychic Research Quarterly, vol.1 no.1. July 1920., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - The social value of logic teaching. The Hibbert Journal. July 1913., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Solipsism. Mind, vol.18, N.S., no.70., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Some problems of mass education. The Personalist, supplement. July 1930., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Thought and immediacy. Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods, vol.3 no.9. April 26, 1906., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - The tribulations of truth. The Albany Review. March 1908., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Truth, value and biology. Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods, vol.17 no.2. January 15, 1920, 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - The two logics. Mind, vol.36, N.S., no.141., 3 copies. (Box 13)
  - The value of formal logic. Mind, vol.41, N.S., no.161., 3 copies. (Box 13)
  - The value of logic. [written with Dr. A. Wolf.] No publisher. Dr. Wolf's section, 1 copy. Dr. Schiller's section., 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - What formal logic is about. Mind, vol.27, N.S., no.108., 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - Why humanism? Contemporary British Philosophy. n.d., 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - Why pluralism? A symposium by J.H. Muirhead, FCS Schiller, and A.E. Taylor. Proceedings of the Aristotelian Society. 1909. (Box 13)
- Letters to Editors
  - Letters to editors. v.p. ca. 1898-1929., 27 items. (Box 13)
- Pamphlets and Articles Concerning FCS Schiller
  - G., B.G. Dr. FCS Schiller. The Pelican Record, vol.23 no.4. December 1937. (Box 13)
  - Lindsay, A.D. University of Oxford Report for the Year. 1936-37. Oxford., 92pp.
  - Livingstone, Sir R.W. College Annual Record. Corpus Christi College, Oxford. 1937.
  - Marrett, R.R. Ferdinand Canning Scott Schiller, 1864-1937. Proceedings of the British Academy, vol.23.
  - Antmen or supermen? [review, author unknown]. Foreign Reviews, vol.1 no.7. 1935.
  - Humanism and Studies in humanism [review, author unknown]. The Athenaeum, no.4440. November 30, 1912.
  - Obituary, [author unknown]. Journal of the Society for Psychical Research, vol.30, no.544.
  - Pragmatism and Kant [author unknown]. The Good European Point of View, no.5. Spring 1906.
- Pamphlets and Articles not Relating to FCS Schiller
  - Acton, H.B. The correspondence theory of truth. Meeting of the Aristotelian Society. April 24, 1935. (Box 13)
  - Bartlett, E.M. The determination of the aesthetic minimum. Meeting of the Aristotelian Society. February 25, 1935. (Box 13)
  - Greenwood, T. The logic of Jules Lachelier. Meeting of the Aristotelian Society. January 28, 1935. (Box 13)
  - Ignotus, Scotus [pseudonym]. The function of Nietzsche, and What is a government? (or Taxing and stealing). [pamphlet]. Mind Association, Oxford. 1914, 20pp. (Box 13)
  - Jeffreys, Harold. Scientific method, causality, and reality. Meeting ot the Aristotelian Society. February 8, 1937. (Box 13)
  - Joad, C.E.M. The element of greatness in philosophy. Meeting of the Aristotelian Society. January 14, 1935. (Box 13)
  - Knox, Howard V. Has Green answered Locke? Mind, vol.23, N.S., no.91. (Box 13)
  - Knox, Howard V. William James and his philosophy. Mind, vol.22, N.S., no.86., 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - Langley, G.H. Freedom and modern political conceptions. Meeting of the Aristotelian Society. January 25, 1937. (Box 13)
  - Listowel, William Francis Hare, earl of. The present state of aesthetics in this country. Meeting of the Aristotelian Society. May 13, 1935. (Box 13)
  - MacMurray, John. The nature of reason. Meeting of the Aristotelian Society. March 25, 1935. (Box 13)
  - Porteous, A.J.D. The idea of necessary connexion. Meeting of the Aristotelian Society. April 8, 1935. (Box 13)
  - Saw, R.L. An aspect of causal connexion. Meeting of the Aristotelian Society. February, 1935. (Box 13)
  - Stout, G.F. Mr. Russell's theory of judgment. No publisher. With extensive notes by FCS Schiller. (Box 13)
  - Weinhandl, Ferdinand. Experimentelle untersuchungen zur psychologie der determinierten abläufe. [pamphlet]. Leipzig, Academische Verlagsgesellschaft M.B.H. 1926., 78pp. (Box 13)
- Newspaper and Magazine Clippings Both Concerning and Not Concerning FCS Schiller
  - 1887-1900., 29 items. (Box 14)
  - 1901., 43 items. (Box 14)
  - 1902., 35 items. (Box 14)
  - 1903., 45 items. (Box 14)
  - 1904., 61 items. (Box 14)
  - 1905-1906., 27 items. (Box 14)
  - 1907., 96 items. (Box 14)
  - 1908., 19 items. (Box 14)
  - 1909., 22 items. (Box 14)
  - 1910., 48 items. (Box 14)
  - 1911., 16 items. (Box 14)
  - 1912., 66 items. (Box 15)
  - 1913., 30 items. (Box 15)
  - 1914., 45 items. (Box 15)
  - 1915-1923., 16 items. (Box 15)
  - 1924., 81 items. (Box 15)
  - 1925., 15 items. (Box 15)
  - 1926., 63 items. (Box 15)
  - 1927-1930., 21 items. (Box 15)
  - 1931-1941., 62 items. (Box 15)
  - n.d., 156 items. (Box 15)
- Scholastic, Legal, Financial, and Medical Papers
  - Scholastic Papers:
    - Reports from school. 1872-1877., 31 items. (Box 16)
    - Certificates (in Latin) from Balliol College, Oxford. 1882-1886., 5 items. (Box 16)
    - Report from Rugby, in the form of a letter from Thomas William Jex-Blake to Mr. Ferdinand Schiller., 1 item. (Box 16)
  - Legal and Financial Papers
    - Correspondence, Legal Agreements, and Accounts Regarding the Following Books or Pamphlets:
      - Cassandra. 1926, and Tantalus. 1924., 12 items. (Box 16)
      - Eugenics and politics. 1926., 4 items. (Box 16)
      - Formal logic. 1912., 7 items. (Box 16)
      - Humanism. 1903, 1 item. (Box 16)
      - Logic for use. 1929., 7 items. (Box 16)
      - Mind! 1901., 4 items. (Box 16)
      - Must philosophers disagree? 1934., 4 items. (Box 16)
      - Plato or Protagoras? 1908., 9 items. (Box 16)
      - Problems of belief. 1924., 1 item. (Box 16)
      - Riddles of the sphinx, 1st edition. 1891., 23 items. (Box 16)
      - Riddles of the sphinx, 2nd edition. 1910., 11 items. (Box 16)
      - Social decay and eugenical reform. 1932., 1 item. (Box 16)
      - Studies in humanism. 1907., 3 items. (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous and unidentified. v.d., 10 items. (Box 16)
    - Papers, correspondence, and ephemera relating to stocks. 1912-1937., 10 items. (Box 16)
      - Prospecti(?) for corporations. n.d., 2 items. (Box 16)
      - Receipts and bills. 1890-1923, v.p., 12 items. (Box 16)
    - Medical Papers:
      - Medical papers. 1923-1934, v.p., 4 items. (Box 16)
- Personal Effects and Ephemera
  - Certificates from University of Southern California:
    - Honorary Fellow of the School of Philosophy. n.d. (Box 17)
    - Degree of Doctor of Laws. n.d. (Box 17)
  - Check book stubs. 1937. (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous printed ephemera, v.p. v.d., 46 items. (Box 16)
  - Booklet. Poor Richard's Almanac. (Box 17)
  - Booklet. What you want to say and how to say it in Spanish. (Box 17)
  - Unused postcards., 2 large and 97 regular sized. (Box 17)
  - Photos of Oxford., 12 items. (Box 17)
  - Leather folders., 2 items. (Box 17)
  - Metal box of 3 compartments, containing 2 keys. (Box 17)
  - Metal paper knife. (Box 17)
  - Wooden Box Containing:
    - Several papers of pins. (Box 17)
    - Metal 3-color crayon. (Box 17)
    - Cloth strap. (Box 17)
    - Leather belt. (Box 17)
    - Nut, bolt, and washer. (Box 17)
- Photographs of FCS Schiller and Miscellaneous Other People
  - Photographs of FCS Schiller in two folders., 5 items. (Box 17)
  - Newspaper photograph showing FCS Schiller standing at bookshelf., 1 item. (Box 17)
  - Photographs of FCS Schiller in the mountains., 2 items. (Box 17)
  - Negatives of pictures of FCS Schiller., 12 items. (Box 17)
  - Caricature of FCS Schiller done with ink and brush, artist unknown. (Box 17)
  - Photographs of FCS Schiller and two other gentlemen [his brothers?] seated outdoors in lawn chairs., 2 items. (Box 17)
  - Photographs of FCS Schiller and his brothers, taken 1877. (Box 17)
    - Photographs of FCS Schiller, labeled Master C. Schiller., 2 items. (Box 17)
    - Photograph of Ferdinand Nassau Schiller, labeled Ferdinand Schiller/July 1877/born August 1866. (Box 17)
    - Photograph of Ferdinand Philip Maximilian Schiller, labeled Master M. Schiller. (Box 17)
  - Photographs of or including FCS Schiller., 49 items. (Box 17)
  - Photographs of mountain-climbing expeditions., 27 items. One photograph shows FCS Schiller and Mrs. Griswold (later his wife). (Box 17)
  - Photographs of elderly woman in late 19th century costume [FCS Schiller' mother?]., 2 items. One with wooden frame. (Box 17)
  - Photograph of a gentleman seated at a desk [one of FCS Schiller' brothers?]. (Box 17)
  - Unidentified photographs., 3 items. (Box 17)
  - Photographs and negatives that do not include FCS Schiller., 31 photographs and 30 negatives. (Box 17)
- Correspondence of Louise Luqueer (Strang) Griswold Schiller
  - Correspondence Relating to FCS Schiller Estate:
    - Chotiner and Chotiner, law firm., 42 letters to Louise Strang Schiller. (Box 18)
    - Fifth Avenue Bank of New York., 2 letters. 1 telegram to Louise Strang Schiller. (Box 18)
    - Williams and James, law firm., 43 letters. 4 telegrams to Louise Strang Schiller. (Box 18)
  - Personal Correspondence of Louise Strang Schiller:
    - Briggs, George A., 1 letter to LSS. (Box 18)
    - Grover, Edwin Osgood, 1870-., 1 letter to LSS. (Box 18)
    - Henderson, Archibald, 1877-., 1 letter to Miss La Rue. (Box 18)
    - Hill, Sir Arthur William, 1875-1941., 1 letter to LSS. (Box 18)
    - KleinSmid, Rufus Bernhard von, 1875-., 1 letter to LSS. (Box 18)
    - Otto, Max Carl, 1876-., 1 letter to Miss La Rue. (Box 18)
    - Perry, Ralph Barton, 1876-., 1 letter to Columbia University Press. (Box 18)
    - Piatt, Donald A., 1 letter to Miss La Rue. (Box 18)
    - The Save the children fund, London., 1 letter to LSS. (Box 18)
    - Schiller, Ferdinand Canning Scott, 1864-1937., 1 letter to LSS. (Box 18)
    - Schiller, Ferdinand Nassau, 1866-1938., 2 letters to LSS. (Box 18)
    - Schiller, Ferdinand Philip Maximilian, 1868-1946., 1 letter to LSS. (Box 18)
    - University of Southern California. (Box 18)
      See KleinSmid, Rufus Bernhard von, 1875-.
    - Vincent, Margaret., 1 letter to LSS. (Box 18)
    - Undecipherable., 1 letter to LSS. (Box 18)
- Manuscripts by Louise Luqueer (Strang) Griswold Schiller
  - Art lectures. n.p. n.d., Typescript. 23 leaves. (Box 18)
  - Assorted Manuscripts. n.p. 1925
    - Schools and the citizen. n.p. 1925., 11 leaves. Typescript. (Box 18)
      Also: 32 leaves, Holograph.
    - Some approaches to the problems of visual art. n.p. n.d., 19 leaves. Typescript. (Box 18)
    - The teaching of the aesthetic arts in secondary schools. n.p. n.d., 9 leaves. Typescript. (Box 18)
  - Journal containing poetry. (Box 18)
  - Poetry and prose. 1910-1940., 70 items. (Box 18)
- Miscellaneous Papers of Louise Luqueer (Strang) Griswold Schiller
  - Legal papers, bills, and receipts., 114 items. (Box 18)
  - Recipes., 4 items. (Box 18)
  - Envelope addressed to Mrs. FCS Schiller. (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous items., 22 items. (Box 18)